Saheb Singh Arora

Faculty of Computer Science Co-op Program

■ +15068975685 Sahebsa.29@unb.ca Fredericton, NB iii in/saheb-singh-arora-9b8135257/ iithub.com/sahebsa

Summary

Saheb Singh Arora, a Computer Science student at the University of New Brunswick, combines a strong academic background with diverse tech experience, including a Java Developer Internship. Skilled in React, AWS, and Python, he has built various projects and actively contributes to extracurriculars, focusing on mental health advocacy and student orientation to hone his leadership skills.

Education

University of New Brunswick

Bachelor of Computer Science, GPA:3.4

Fredericton, Canada 2022-Present

Professional Experience

Product Demonstrator (Club Demonstration Service (Costco))

Fredericton, NB 12/2022 - 09/2024

• Market Costco products to the customers. Provide samples and demos for products. Meet sale targets.

Facility Operator, (University of New Brunswick)

Fredericton, NB 05/2023 - 07/2023

• Managed UNB Gym section and various events in a team.

Java Developer Intern, (Immortal Computer Lab Pvt Ltd)

Mumbai, IN 05/2022 - 08/2022

• Successfully completed a post-12th grade internship as a Java Developer Intern, acquiring new skills in jForm and Swing controls.

Projects

Personal Portfolio 2024

Created a personal portfolio website using HTML and CSS, showcasing my experience, skills, and projects. The site includes options to download my CV and has buttons linking to my GitHub and LinkedIn profiles, all designed with a focus on responsive design and clean, well-structured code.

To-do List 2024

Created a to-do list application using React.js that allows users to easily add, remove, and mark tasks as completed. The project demonstrates proficiency in front-end development and effective state management, providing a seamless user experience.

Chatbot (GenAl) 2024

Using AWS Lex V2 for building conversational ChatBot and Lambda functions using Python for Message response cards. This combination allows for powerful and flexible chatbot development, integrating natural language understanding. AWS bedrock is used to generate automated utterances. This was a group project done by my classmate and me.

E commerce using React

2023

An e-commerce website built using React and Typescript, where we can filter clothes products using their customer preferred sizes as M, L or XL etc. We have a button called "Add to cart" below each product shown on the web page, once user selects any product, it will go to cart. At the end it can be used to checkout.

Online shopping application

2022

GUI based java application which allows users to add items to the shopping cart, delete items for the cart and finally proceed to the checkout which allows to choose payment gateways. Also generates an unique ticket id per user. The application is attached to Mysql database which stores user details for every submitted record.

Python Game development

2022

Python Snake Game is a classic arcade-style game where players control a snake on a grid- based playing field. The snake changes colour based on the given conditions and parameters

Certifications

National Cyber Olympiad	2016,2017,2018
International Math Olympiad	2016,2017,2018,2021,2022
National science Olympiad	2021,2022
NELTAS English Proficiency Exam	2021
Ethical Hacking and Forensics(IIT BOMBAY)	2020
Introduction to Python Programming(IIT BOMBAY)	2020

Technical Skills

Programming: Java, C++, Python, C, React, Typescript, SQL, MVC. **Technologies:** AWS, Github, Linux OS, Mac OS, Microsoft Windows

Volunteer Experience

- ISAO welcome event for new students, Collaborated with a team of volunteers to manage the welcome desk, ensuring smooth operations and providing a welcoming atmosphere for new students. Developed problem-solving and organizational skills by handling various responsibilities, including checkins and registration.
 - UNB Redshirts, Led and collaborated with a diverse team
 of volunteers to coordinate multiple orientation events,
 ensuring a smooth and welcoming experience. Took
 initiative in various roles, seamlessly switching between
 leadership and supportive positions to meet the dynamic
 needs of the team and the event.

Clubs and Societies

• Mental Health Association, at the University of New Brunswick (UNB) is a student-led club focused on promoting positive mental health attitudes and practices. The club organizes a variety of activities, events, and discussions aimed at breaking down the stigma surrounding mental health issues. Additionally, it engages in fundraising activities to support the Canadian Mental Health Association (CMHA). This involvement provides a platform for students to learn about, discuss, and advocate for mental health awareness in a supportive community setting

Academic Awards

2022-2023 UNB Scholarship for Academic Excellence